Zoë Rosen

0405-432-787 au.linkedin.com/in/zoerosen zoe@anthrochick.com www.anthrochick.com.

Objectives

I want to be in the future of human centered design. I adore the strategy and research process behind shaping customer experience. UX marries into my academic skills in anthropology and philosophy and my love of working with people.

Education

IDEO, Human Centered Design, 2016 General Assembly, User Experience Design Immersive, 2015 Macquarie University, B.A. Anthropology & Philosophy, 2013 University of Sydney, Continuing Education, Conflict Management, 2012

Experience

Cochlear CTLD (November 2016 - Current)

Cochlear Implants for the Profoundly Deaf UX Designer

Facilitating and coordinating research into Cochlear audiological software internationally. Assisting in establishing documentation protocol for regulatory bodies. Providing research training for insight discovery and usability testing practice for early stage project concepts.

Allianz Australia (6 months)

Global Insurance Provider CX Researcher

High level strategy development of the CX framework for implementation across Allianz Australia. Planning and facilitation of CX research for primary business channels to develop Allianz's strategic direction. Plan, facilitated and trained staff on research methods, Contextual Inquiries, insight discovery and development and facilitated service design workshops.

Commonwealth Bank Australia (6 months)

Digital Channels UX Researcher, 2015-16

Identifying and facilitating appropriate research methods to generate robust data. Employing both quantitative and qualitative research on customer facing products and reporting directly back to stakeholders. Methods; usability testing, in depth interviews, interception testing, surveys, workshops.

R/GA (4 months)

Digital Media Agency

Lead UX Researcher, 2015.

Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC)

Facilitated contextual research into ABC to determine viewer perception and preferences. Additional research was conducted to understand attitudes and motivations of division heads. Artifacts created; Customer Journey maps, empathy maps, personas, and strategic recommendations and workshops to assist in vision alignment between ABC division heads.

ANZ

Discovery into cultural and organization barriers to ANZ's internal volunteering program; Research conducted to understand current state and experience of volunteer programs end to end; Contextual inquiry, motivation insight generation, persona's and trigger recommendations to adjust behavior.

Perceptive Ideas (2 months)

Human Centered Research and Design Consultancy. UX Research Consultant, 2015

Commonwealth Bank

Assisted Channels

Facilitated CI's and ethnographic work around Concierge teams in branches across Sydney. Compiled data and analysis of key technology usage and identified existing work-a-rounds. Generated crucial scenario maps, insights, persona types, behavioral maps, space usage maps. Provided recommendations to improve customer service and staff management.

ANTHROCHICK

UX Consultant, 2015

Namegear (2 months)

Domain registration site based in Japan.

Website Redesign

Target market identification and strategic direction plan. Provided expert heuristic evaluation, user testing, interviews, competitive analysis, survey development and distribution. Developed journey maps, personas generation, wire frames and digital prototype following human centred design research and fast iteration processes.

Books & Craft (1 month)

Boutique business creates personalised notebooks and photo albums to order.

Business production barrier identification. Client scenario maps, solution scenarios. Wire framing, iteration and adaption, interactive prototype generation to stage ready for development. Result; internal facing ordering application system for the client.

Miss Freya Baska's Art School

Brand Experience Designer, 2015

Art Therapy school founded on Rudolf Steiner's Educational Philosophy.

Created high level growth strategy, CX principles, development of tone of voice guide, and UX review.

The Customer Experience Company (5 months)

Management Consulting, UX Design, Sydney CBD, 2014

Consulting firm focusing on human centered design, culture change and customer strategy.

Rabobank & Rabodirect

Facilitated contextual inquires and interviews of regional and metro customers and staff in Australia and New Zealand. Generating insights regarding banking decisions, accounting and satisfaction. Explored staff motivations, and loyalty. Generated personas and reported back to key stakeholders in Sydney.

Westpac and BT Wealth Technology.

Ethnographic researched into workplace behavior and team dynamics. Implementing observational techniques to surface existing cultural attitudes. Identified key elements within the company structure and implemented cultural change strategies to encourage behavioral change and encourage collaboration and trust. Reported directly to CIO.

IAG (Insurance Australia Group)

Facilitated usability tests on Home and Car Insurance mobile apps. Developed wireframes, customer journey maps and user insights.

Department of Justice (Parramatta)

Organization culture change strategy development. Responsible for team policy research and updates. Contextual inquiry research and interviews, interview/ data analysis, organization structure analysis, role description creation and strategies for implementation of culture and business structure change.

ACI (Agency for Clinical innovation)

Script writing, filming, audio and footage editing (Final Cut Pro) for short information video to be distributed across NSW medical centers.

Beaurepairs/ Goodyear

Editing footage/audio to create training material for internal distribution (Final Cut Pro).

Service NSW

Website user testing, analysis insight generation and customer maps.

National Geographic & University of Witwatersrand,

Research Assistant & Logistics 2013 – 14

Rising Star Expedition,

The Expedition was funded by National Geographic, the expedition team discovered a new species of early hominid, the recently announced Homo Naledi species. Documentary "Dawn of Humanity", NOVA and PBS, 2015. 'Almost Human' National Geographic, October edition, 2015.

Core Research Knowledge/Skills

- Ethnography
- Contextual Inquiry

- Design Thinking
- · Accessibility

- Usability
- Survey
- Guerrilla
- Persona Development

- · Cultural influencers
- UX Strategy Development
- Mental Models development
- Research and Insight development Training

Computer Skills

- Final Cut Pro, Advanced
- POP, Advanced
- · Microsoft Office, Advanced
- Axure, Medium
- Sketch, Medium
- · Qualtrics, Advanced
- · NVivo, Advanced

Volunteer

Allianz Guest Lecturer

Lecture, October 2016

'What is Design Thinking?' Introduction to Design Thinking and what it means for Allianz.

General Assembly Guest Lecturer

Lecture, Feb 2016

'What is Design Thinking in Hard Science?' Hour talk to evening design immersive students.

CBA Guest Lecture

Lecture, Nov, 2015

'Designing for Empathy'. Hour talk about the neuro-science behind empathy, how to cultivate it and what concepts like "practical empathy" mean.

Sydney Design Thinking Meet Up.

Co-coordinator, 2015 - Current

We are the largest Design Thinking group in the Southern Hemisphere with over 3000 members. We have speakers from various backgrounds who talk about different aspects of Design Thinking.

http://www.meetup.com/Sydney-Design-Thinking-Meetup/events/223463652/